<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Creative on Dahlia Zhou's Blog</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/categories/creative/</link><description>Recent content in Creative on Dahlia Zhou's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:49:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/categories/creative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Middle School Year 1</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/middle-school-year-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:49:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/middle-school-year-1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/middle-school-year-1/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Middle School Year 1" />&lt;h1 id="chapter-1---encounter">Chapter 1 - Encounter&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>That was a summer to remember. This was a summer with no assignments and boring extracurricular classes. Zi ran around the whole neighbourhood with her best friend, Ming. A regular summer day included buying a K-pop magazine, finding a spare bench on a public street, and thirsting after the unrealistically-beautiful boy brand member.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was 2009. Beijing just recovered from the frenzy of an internationally-proclaimed Olympic Games. Despite the western economic in decline, China was in its hay-day. QQ was filled with propaganda claiming the western media smeared our opening ceremonies through deliberate poor camera skills, and Zhang Yimo’s China was much more glorious. Zi angrily pressed “repost” on all the exposé, cursing the Europeans under her breath. Those negative thoughts didn’t stay with her long, though. Her 20-min internet allowance at grandma’s house was not to be wasted. She frequented internet chat rooms, blocking perverted middle-aged men left and right. Other than that, she prided herself in already reading smuts from K-pop fan-fiction sites, but by no way understood what “sex” actually was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both Zi and Ming went to the same elementary school and were heading to the same middle school. They lived around the same area, and both had chubby cheeks and silly demeanour. But there was something that made them different: Zi was about to go to one of the top classes, while Ming one of the bottom classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here was something that set Chinese education apart. Kids were ranked at a very young age, and those who scored lower on a test were publicly shamed. Zi remembered the teacher harshly throwing the test paper on Ming’s face and loudly demeaning her for scoring poorly. Before a student could head to middle school, the excellent students, those who were class presidents and had better grades, were sent for a lottery to be assigned to different schools. That was the first tier of students. Zi did well in class, but she didn’t really participate in any of the “class activities” she deemed pretentious and preformative. She wasn’t recommended to the school district to be in the lottery. Instead, she went in and did a test with the school. 10,000 yuan later, she was promised to be in the top class (1-4). This process was for the second tier students, those who were smart but less “well-behaved”. Then there was the last tier of students. These students were the “degenerates”, the ones deemed “failures” in the parents’ eyes. After the first and second tier of students had their pick of the schools, they were entered into a lottery, randomly assigned to the “bottom classes” (5-8) of middle schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zi didn’t care about that. She was just exuberant that she got to go to the same school as Ming. You might say, “of course she wouldn’t care! She’s a kid”. Well, you’d be surprised how many kids in Beijing developed this early sense of “class” and how the “good” students avoided the “bad” like the plague. The top-tier students with their fancy workbook and little mechanical pencil rolled their eyes at the students who did poorly in math or English. Zi was not about that. She was raised better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The summer eventually came to an end. Zi had to be back to her parents’. Her parents were fine, but she much preferred her gentle, caring grandma and the chef grandpa who could whip up an impressive meal. Her dad frequently chastised her for “being on the phone too much” while her mom criticized all her emotional outbursts. She locked herself in the room, messaging Ming all day. This was when texts were charged individually. Soon her grandma, who was the rightful owner of the phone number, called to tell her she had overspent hundreds. And that was the end of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First day, Zi headed to the school. She discovered that she was sent to class 1. She did a little dance in her head. Class 1 was the prestigious position to be, and she didn’t expect to be placed with the first-tiers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She saw Han right away. Han was in her elementary class and one of those first-tier students. For context, Zi’s middle school was one of the worst in the district, infamous for public brawls and “gang” activities. Zi remembered how Han and several other “good” students broke into tears and huddled to cry because they were placed in the middle school that Zi was honoured to be at. Talking about dramatics. Zi rolled her eyes in her head and waved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Han signalled for her to sit, so she did. Han opted for a more stressful summer, involving coming to the middle school with some future classmates to do some extracurricular classes. Han gestured to the girl sitting next to her, “Hey, Zi, this is a friend I made during summer. Her name is Yue.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zi was not ready for socializing, and she was not ready to see a girl with a boyish haircut and tomboy demeanour. “Oh shit, I thought they were a boy.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yue made an awkward smirk that would become her signature way of expressing annoyance and disgust. Neither one of them knew that this encounter would be the beginning of endless shenanigans for the years to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yue made an introduction that Zi zoned out during the half of. Typical first-tiers. Excellent grades, class president, blah blah. Zi counted the minutes till she could rush to class 6 to meet Ming. Ming delivered the news in the morning, and Zi was excited to meet some cool people from the bottom class. Oh, she really thought she was the rebel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She dragged her heavy bag to the door of class 6, a behaviour the school was against. Bags must be on shoulders. Out was Ming. Zi gave her a big hug, and they squeaked excitedly as the teenagers they were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following Zi was a boy. He was a bit chubby with milk soft skin. The way he walked and waved was feminine and demure. Ming introduced, “This is Xu.” Zi said hi without thinking much, then another boy popped out of the classroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was tall, slim, and tanned.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Jizhidexiaohailang&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Unsplash&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Short Story Collection</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 21:54:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Short Story Collection" />&lt;p>Not good enough to stand alone, but collectively, not so bad huh?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stranger">Stranger&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/andrew-welch-Y-RyEJ8eqHc-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="630"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/andrew-welch-Y-RyEJ8eqHc-unsplash_hu3fd7a9ce6b7f1428a5b7949ef0b49adb_48138_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/andrew-welch-Y-RyEJ8eqHc-unsplash_hu3fd7a9ce6b7f1428a5b7949ef0b49adb_48138_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by andrew welch on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="101"
data-flex-basis="243px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your mischievous smile lit up the dim corner of the run-down dive bar. You look familiar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hand that laid down the first brick of the Great Wall. The noise came from the Colosseum while the gladiators fought to their deaths. The dust registered by the hooves of the ferocious Genghis Khan Army. The gasp while Marco Polo’s tale of the Far East was spreading in the rustic farm town. The rancid smoke from the burning barn carrying patients of the Black Death. The resounding gunfire while the Spanish set foot in a fruitful yet foreign land. The applause after Shakespeare enchanted the audience with his first play. The trenches filled with victories and losses of the brutal war.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You came close to me and whispered in my ear, “Have I seen you before?” Yes, you have. Too many times. I reached my hand out and you grabbed it. “No.” I said. Music drowned out your laughter and the neon light diluted your gorgeous eyes. Hello again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-griefing-period">The Griefing Period&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/mayron-oliveira-mibn6LLm9kA-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="427"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/mayron-oliveira-mibn6LLm9kA-unsplash_hu0d404f77f177f2f3409c1daf74a446c4_63099_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/short-story-collection/mayron-oliveira-mibn6LLm9kA-unsplash_hu0d404f77f177f2f3409c1daf74a446c4_63099_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Mayron Oliveira on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="149"
data-flex-basis="359px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I met you at her funeral. I came down, missing her laughter and her eyes curved like the crescent moon. You were standing in your wrinkled black suit. Flicking the cigarette were your fingers reddened by the cold. You were her lover. At the eulogy, your deep voice was shaking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That night, I called you crying, missing her nightly calls to me before depression took away her spark. The other end of the phone call was filled with sadness only describable by your silence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We bonded through our love for her. Her kindness, the little poem she wrote both of us, her finger nails bitten to so short, and how gorgeously her dress flew in the wind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your paint brush dirtied your denim overall. The paint stroke chaotically came together to depict nothing but the breathtaking her. We let the sunset reflect on the painting. She was alive again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I felt her energy when I was with you. Every breath you took she came out once again, standing at the end of the hallway, head resting on the window, eyelashes shining from her tears filled with melancholy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I told you I loved you, you didn’t even question it. Your breath was deep and warm. The room was boiling. Condensation covered the only window in the studio. In the painting, she stared back, emotionless. Your sad eyes stared down, still breathless. This was a mistake. You said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why did we make the same mistake so many times after? Did we fall in love with each other, or did we fall in love with grievance? Her shadow was ineradicable and followed us around. We could not talk about anything but how much we missed her. Is it wrong that we are doing this? I asked. You said nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was our healing process, I supposed. You stopped replying to my texts. Calls left unanswered. You put her behind, and I was the last bit of her remaining in your life waiting to be erased. I missed our late night sorrow and grieving, how your long and well-manicured fingers felt on my skin, the paint that was scattered onto my expensive clothing, and most importantly, how sad and in pain we both were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I couldn’t blame you. I stopped thinking about her as much. She made me too sad, too vulnerable, and too unstable. I stopped bursting into tears out of nowhere. The same brand of perfume no longer made my eyes red. Funny how fast we forgot someone we loved so deeply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I prayed to see you again, but my last message to you was left on read for months and months. Your studio light was on, but I no longer had the courage to step into that room full of memories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess that’s how most stories end. The concert jungle of our city dominated the limit of our sadness. We could only stay stagnant so long, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Richard Payette&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Unsplash&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Wedding</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 17:49:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Wedding" />&lt;p>The banquet hall was decorated with the most delicate flowers and luscious white silk. Caterers dressed in black and white swiftly passed by crowds of guests who were engaged in mindless mingling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dana anxiously wiped away the champagne residue on the corner of her mouth with the pristine white cloth. Her newly touched-up lips left a smudge of redness. She sighed. The weather in St. Louis was particularly unbearable in the summer. She was anxious that she had to skip an important conference 1000 km away. Her phone had been blowing up all morning. Her companion was anxious in a different manner. His quiescent nature rendered every social situation somewhat uncomfortable at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She texted her friend Yasmin, while replying to the last 5 emails. She anxiously tapped her high heels. Yasmin was one of the few friends she kept in touch since middle school. Proudly open and queer, yet conserved and wildly religious, Yasmin painted a picture of contradiction. Chicago was merely 400 km away, across two state lines, while Dana had to take an early morning flight to cross the northern border. Dana frowned. Why was she late?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next through the door was Olivia. Dana quickly waved, while praying the grouping was intentional and not randomized. The fashion in wedding was now the encouragement of mingling and networking. Dana knew she’d be on the first flight the next morning and would rather the bride blessed her with an easy night of conversations. Olivia had been steadily climbing in her career in architecture. Sometimes Dana would see Olivia’s building while on business trips to Atlanta. Despite small and intimate, Olivia’s design had always been outstanding. Olivia did not bring a plus one. She showed up in an artistic and alternative dress with eccentric pattern. In lieu of high heels, Olivia chose a pair of yellow flats. Dana rolled her eyes in her mind but welcomed Olivia with a warm smile, “Thank god you are here! I’m bored. I don’t know anybody.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They exchanged small chatter about their career. Dana updated Olivia on her current marital and career status. She introduced herself with a smirk. A married 35-year-old with a gleaming career, she thought of herself as every career woman’s dream. Olivia refused the champagne offered by the waitress and started to list her upcoming projects. A rising star in the architect world, Olivia chose a more demure but not less exciting life: Frequent visits to art galas and social events with celebrity, yet she continued to be dedicated to art and not finance. Dana hammered Olivia’s on her relationship status, in which she replied, “I’m too busy to settle down.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Dana and Olivia were engaging in rounds and rounds of more competition than conversation, Scarlett walked in with Leah. Dana raised her brows. These two had been flown in from China. They were both followed by their husband. Dana knew them from the pictures. Scarlett married a young music professor looked particularly handsome in the tuxedo he normally posed in. Leah met an older but good-looking heir to some state fortune through her parents and got married in less than a year. Dana jumped up and gave both of them a quick hug and allowed the men to initiate their side conversation. “It’s been so long!” Dana had not seen either of these women in at least four years, “How are you?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scarlett went and started describing her music education career. As a young university post-doc, she had been fighting the university politics to finally get the professor position. If all things went well, she would be a full-time professor the next fall. Dana passed the hot tea Leah ordered instead of champagne, while she started to describe the headache of a new mother. After her chronic illness had taken away most of her energy, Leah had dedicated her life into raising her child. &amp;ldquo;A lucky son. &amp;quot; Her eyes glistened. Dana quickly swallowed the last drop of champagne in her glass and added to the conversation, “my daughter started speaking when she was only 10 months, but boys start slow.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/deleece-cook-znXmpb53QJU-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="466"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/deleece-cook-znXmpb53QJU-unsplash_hu6575cd830d9a87380b71759a18cf2025_69810_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/deleece-cook-znXmpb53QJU-unsplash_hu6575cd830d9a87380b71759a18cf2025_69810_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Deleece Cook on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="137"
data-flex-basis="329px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, Yasmin was here. Dana sighed with relief. Yasmin walked in with her usual child-like demeanour. In a dark blue suit, she had an older lady in her arm. Yasmin married her wife after years of turmoil. Her wife starting seeing her before ending her previous marriage. After playing the role of the other woman for many years, Yasmin finally came out on top and became the official spouse. Outside of her tumultuous love life, Yasmin was the producer of a TV station. Last year, Yasmin gave Dana a tour of the studio. As an ex-filmmaker, Dana felt the immense guilt that she left art behind, while picking up a quick call outside the recording studio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yasmin hugged everyone and sat down the name tag with the leaf symbol. Dana laughed, “Don’t you hate these stupid labels?” Yasmin laughed loudly, while Leah shrugged, “They are kinda cute.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then came the maid of honour, Yara. She covered herself in a muted yet gorgeous pink gown decorated with carefully designed flowers. Dana forced an awkward smile. When Yara got married, Dana was left out of the invitation along with Yasmin because of their collective animosity towards the groom. Dana disliked Yara’s husband, who was their middle school classmate that had once expressed interests in several other girls simultaneously. Unlike Yara who was born with a silver spoon under her short dark hair, her husband grew up dirt poor. He could hardly afford the ring on Yara’s fingers. Dana cursed him under her breath, but refused to display any discomfort. Yara had no stable job, but somehow was always travelling the world with her mom’s bank accounts. Dana and Leah looked at each other with a knowing glance. They both disliked Yara to a certain extent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yara smiled, “so glad you guys came! Especially Scarlett and Leah, all the way from China. How was the flight?” Leah was just about to speak while Scarlett took over the mic quickly, “Torture, but Hazel is getting married. We ought to be here!” Do we? Dana murmured to herself. They haven’t spoken for at least four years. Hazel was the prettiest girl in the group back in the day. Her smile had all the guys in the school mesmerized. As an ugly duckling herself, Dana had always been jealous of Hazel’s popularity. Despite growing attractive herself, Dana was still unsettled by how the amount of bullying in middle school had exacerbated her competitive nature. It must’ve easy being pretty and perfect all her life. Dana chugged another glass of champagne. Hazel had been working for an ad agency doing copywriting with her talent for language. Her soon-to-be husband’s father owned a business that made millions. A luxurious wedding. Dana thought of her own intimate yet casual wedding and moaned at the waste of money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dana looked around the table. Yasmin had her arm around her wife. Still in their honeymoon stage. Dana frowned, while watching her own husband across from her indulging in an impassioned yet random conversation with one of the other husbands. Olivia and Scarlett exchanged knowledge on education and art. They had always been the artsy type. Leah was quietly sipping on her hot tea while Yara bragging about the child-free life she led with her jobless husband. Dana touched Leah’s hand, “How is your health?” Leah looked up, “Better!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ceremony soon started. Hazel came out in a laced mermaid dress. Every inch of the dress was covered in shimmering crystals, and the delicate laces interlaced with the shines ever so perfectly. “You know my wedding dress was a simple white dress that barely cost 100 right?” Dana whispered to Yasmin. “I didn’t even have a wedding.” Yasmin laughed. Dana remembered the little wedding dinner at a small restaurant, where Yasmin shed a tear while talking about the absence of her parents. Dana sighed, watching Hazel finishing her vows while wearing that huge rock on her fingers. Hazel looks especially stunning with her bejewelled thick dark hair. The tear marks on her cheek made her look vulnerable and lovable. The emotion of the ceremony moved the entire room of guests. Even Dana felt the soreness surrounded her eyes. Yara got up and gave a quick speech. Yara and Hazel met the same time as the rest of them. As girls with broken families, they formed a much stronger bond. Yara made sure to mention the table they used to dine at in the cafeteria and expressed awe of the presence of every single member. “Can you believe it?” Olivia broke the silence, “it’s been more than 20 years. And we got to meet again. ”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It had been more than two decades since the seven of them became friends. The world had not stopped spinning for a single second. Dana had gone through several career changes and climbed the corporate ladder to where she was today. Yasmin fought tooth and nails to marry the love of her life, despite having almost everyone in the world against their marriage. Olivia pursued her dream and never in one second doubted her ability in architecture. Scarlett played the politics and finally got closer to what she deserved. Leah went through a tough time with her illness and now had a beautiful family of her own. Yara chose love over the prejudice of others. And Hazel, despite going through many difficult years as a child of an alcoholic mother, believed that she could be happy and deserve someone who loved her. Today, they had gathered together once again. Despite the long history of conflicts, animosity, and cliquey infighting, they sat together, each accomplished in their different way. Even though they had not been friends for at least one decade, they still led their separate yet full life outside that lunch table they used to sit together at. Who knows when they would be together again? Life had been consuming every single one of them’s energy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/mche-lee-PC91Jm1DlWA-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="480"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/mche-lee-PC91Jm1DlWA-unsplash_hu40750fa3bda66facae31b6d6797a99f2_49425_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/the-wedding/mche-lee-PC91Jm1DlWA-unsplash_hu40750fa3bda66facae31b6d6797a99f2_49425_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by MChe Lee on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in the days, similar to the plot of Mean Girls, they were the popular-ish girls in the school. Hazel, Yara, and Leah were the three prettiest girls in their grade, smart and beautiful. Dana, Yasmin, Scarlett, and Olivia were the ugly ducklings who were unique in their own ways. Hazel and Yara would talk about the boys who sent the love letters. Despite equally pretty, Leah had always distanced herself from the other two pretty girls. Leah, Dana, and Yasmin had their own tight-knit clique, roaming around campus by engaging in brainless banters. Scarlett and Olivia were the outsiders of the lunch clique, but their presence always added new gossip to the mundaneness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their unexpected friendship had all kinds of twist-and-turns. Dana remembered Yara tore up her diary with Hazel’s name after Hazel getting a love letter from a boy Yara liked. Yasmin and Dana also fought viciously over celebrities or that one female classmate Yasmin fell head over heels for. Leah frequently made snarky comments on Yara’s flamboyance. Dana rolled her eyes at Hazel’s ploy to get more boy’s attention that she was already getting. The table broke up multiple times throughout that three years. Eventually, the seven people lunch table became a rarity. Yara moved to a fancy school far away. Dana, Yasmin, and Leah started their own lunch table. Scarlett and Olivia found their new home during this hour. And Hazel floated between different tables. The last time they shared a table like they were doing at this wedding would be at least 18 or 19 years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through the two decades of on-and-off friendship, the seven of them got into enough trouble with each other. Yara’s rash decision to elope and Yasmin’s secret love affairs had ruffled a few feathers. An all-girl friend group could not devoid itself of gossiping and small fighting, but they grew to tolerate the little friction among each other, knowing they had established a friendship larger than themselves. The connection between them seven was beyond simple joy and support. It became the only reminder of the innocent days of middle school. They fought through all the trouble to remain connected. Despite not speaking for at least four years, Hazel remembered to gather all of them for a night of booziness and celebration. Despite the drama and the busy schedule, all six of them decided to drop everything and show up. Dana knew that she did not catch a flight, and spent a suspiciously large amount of time bickering with the TSA agent so that she could simply show her respect. In some way, she was delighted to be here. These women reminded her of her pubescent years as the awkward and chubby girl who dared to dream big. They reminded her the little secrets they used to share and the childish fights they engaged in to show how much they care for each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dana soon had too much to drink. Yasmin’s silly jokes started to fade away and become the blurry background noise. Hazel soon came over. Dana stumbled and grabbed her into a tight hug. “Congratulations.” She mumbled, “thank you for the invitation.” Hazel laughed, her laugh still as crispy as it was back in the days. “Thank you all for coming.” Dana remembered Hazel used to see her off the bus, and yelled to the crowd &amp;ldquo;Please stay alive! &amp;quot; in an attempt to embarrass the already-awkward teen Dana. “Please stay alive and live harder.” Dana cheered to the table. The women who understood the joke burst into laughter. Dana looked around the table, she hadn’t been the jokester of the group for many years after her serious focus on career and usual character as the intense woman. All of a sudden, she was transformed to that table in the cafeteria, being roasted by the other five while being self-deprecating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dana’s husband reminded her that the flight was early the next morning. Dana put down the last glass of champagne. Yasmin explained she and her wife had a hotel room booked for the weekend. “Love that for you. I have to fly back to Toronto for an important meeting.” Dana drunkenly slammed down her drink and rested her head on her husband’s shoulder. “Bye all! See you at the next wedding!” The table turned around and started at Olivia, the only single woman among all of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olivia laughed, “or the next funeral.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dana stepped into the cab. The city draped its bright neon light on her barely open eyelids. She murmured to herself, “I should’ve never come. I’m going to be so hungover tomorrow.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This piece is dedicated to the six of us who are destined to suffer longer and the one girl who left too early. While we are growing older and apart, she remains beautiful and youthful in our slowly fainting memory. I wish I had a chance to say goodbye. On that subway we used to take, I jokingly told her that she would marry a gorgeous, successful man in a white suit. Her slightly curved lips told me that all that she ever wanted. Throughout her life, she dreamed to be loved and adored, yet the world has failed her by showing her unbearable cruelty. Well, she got to get married to a man she loved in this story. Not only that, her wedding was luxurious and stunning, accompanied by all of us, wishing nothing but happiness for her, just like she dreamed. And yes, I will try to stay alive for as long as I can, as I promised.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Beatriz Pérez Moya&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Unsplash&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Mission</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/mission/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/mission/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/mission/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Mission" />&lt;h2 id="5-days-till-the-mission">5 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Her laptop displays the elegant page of a jewelry store that centers on a pair of simmering gold earrings. In the note section, a short sentence reads &amp;ldquo;9-inch chain, one bracelet, one earring - Amy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She quickly closes the laptop when her son comes in. His adolescent sweat stinks up half the room. She tightens her brows, &amp;ldquo;Take a shower.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A recording pops up on her phone for review. She has done this plenty of times. It’s amusing how much more you start to learn once you have joined the force. On the recording, a young woman, presumably Amy, whispers to the microphone, confirming the order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flowers in her yard are blooming gorgeously on this early summer day. The neighbour waves at her when she comes out to collect the mail. Her phone buzzes. Two addresses pop up in the text preview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beauty of the organization is that almost everything is autonomous and anonymous. No one in the organization has access to the information of a pickup, drop-off, or host family. She doesn’t know who started the organization or even who is in the organization besides the handful of host families she has personally met. No one but the algorithm knows that she will have to be at this first address in 5 days, pick up some scared young woman named Amy, and drop her off at the second address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her hands sweat profusely when the thought of the mission pops up in her head. She drops her phone by accident. Her neighbour smiles, and she shrugs. Three mindless chatters and a half later, she closes the door.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-days-till-the-mission">4 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fifteen years ago, she was in a similar situation. Teenage and pregnant. She wore the baggy hoodie on top of her fragile little body in and out of the rundown apartment to hide the increasingly noticeable baby bump and the bruises. The baby’s father was ten years her senior, with the smell of lcohol on his breath and clumsy body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She had nobody after her mother passed away. The world was closing in on her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She usually barely conversed with anybody except the shopkeep while shopping for groceries. One day, the sweet and gentle old lady who always browsed magazines at the bodega stopped her. She was flustered, but the old lady had a voice serene like a jar of marmalade. “Are you in some kind of trouble, sweetheart?” She remembered what the old lady said. She rushed home, hands shivering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since that night, every time she went to the bodega, she would be stopped by the old lady for a small chat. Her baby bump started to protrude from even her baggiest hoodie. The man at home was still merciless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, she told the old lady everything. She remembered they hid under the hood of the tiny bodega while the falling rain poured, the old lady’s wrinkled hand on her recovering bruises.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A month later, closer to the baby’s due date, while the man was snoring after yet another drunken rage, she took everything she owned. She took the leap of faith and got into that white sedan with the hazard light blinking in the middle of the night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She decides to drive to the first address after work to familiarize herself with the area. The address is near a park in the middle of the city. Nearby some kids are screaming in glee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She steps out of the car to explore the area. The sky is sapphire blue. She wonders how close this place is to Amy’s house. Her mind wanders back to the shabby apartment with the rusted fire exit. She wonders if Amy is as tiny and clueless as she was, staring out of the window, counting the seconds till the escape. She even wonders if any of the accompanying women in the park is indeed Amy, putting on a fake smile with strenuous effort, pulling up her top to hide any evidence of dismay.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-days-till-the-mission">3 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Her son is sick today. He locks himself up in the basement. She can hear his loud voice leak through the basement door while squandering another day playing video games. She sighs while putting the coffee cups away and drives off to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She still remembers how hard the pregnancy was. She spent a lot of time going in and out of the doctor’s office. She remembers the stern face of the doctor while explaining that the lack of nutrition throughout the first half of her pregnancy may lead to some health concerns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The host family offered to pay for supplements and bought baby clothes and toys. She cooked and cleaned even though the host family insisted on her resting most of the day. For the rest of the days, she hid in the house, refusing to expose to sunlight. She spent the next five years looking over her shoulder and waking up in the middle of the night in cold sweats. She saw herself a thousand times back in the suffocating room with the man’s snoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the baby turned one, she decided to move out of the host family. She never had a job, nor did she have anybody. The welfare cheque the host family helped her sign up for was abysmal. She had to get a job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her elderly neighbour watched the baby for most days while she ran around the neighbourhood looking for minimum wage jobs. The thrifted blouse had lost its original colour and barely fit her body. She had never had a job nor made a cent on her own. So when the first paycheque arrived, she cried.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She arrives at her office. She is an accountant working for a mid-level corporation. The water cooler talks are bland and repetitive, but she feels blessed listening to Debbie complaining about her 20-year-old daughter. She calls her son around noon and remind him of the pasta she left in the fridge. He frequently goes all day without eating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He has asked her about his father before, but she tells him that she will tell him more once he turns 18. When he was younger, he would always get upset about not having a father. She did all she could to provide for him and comfort him. He is now a respectful teenager with an appropriate amount of pent-up anger and brainless behaviours. He has adjusted well to the world though the first couple of years of his existence was chaotic and brutal. Last year on Mother’s Day, he bought her a bouquet with his lousy handwriting. She still keeps the card in her drawer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-days-till-the-mission">2 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The city starts to pour. The drive back home is wet and blurry. She turns off the radio and sits in silence for a bit. The phone vibrates. It’s a reminder of the mission. “A delivery is scheduled for 2:30 am.” The coldness of the message feels almost industrial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The truth is hidden under the glittery cover of a jewelry delivery.
She got involved with the organization by accident. One of her close friends familiar with her experience confided in her and told her about the organization. Over the alcohol scent of the late-night cocktail, she decided to apply through the website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this enormous and mysterious web of men and women, who believe in rescuing women in abusive relationships who cannot escape through their means, comes together in this organization, anonymously hoping to save one life at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Someone experiencing domestic violence can choose to purchase a 9-inch chain, one bracelet, and one earring. It stands for 911. The system will first confirm the order or that there is indeed a woman in need by calling the number provided. The confirmation will be replayed to multiple participants of the transfers to ensure authenticity. Then the system automatically schedules a series of transfers to avoid having the victim being tracked by the abuser. A woman in need may go through 3 to 5 host families before settling down in one family. Another transfer may be scheduled anytime if the woman feels like their safety is compromised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She didn’t have such an organized support system back in the day. The driver who picked her up was the son of the elderly lady, and the host family was his friend’s. They did the best they could with the limited recourses, but she has always been grateful. These people who were strangers risked their safety and sacrificed their security to protect a woman whom they barely knew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though the host family is more than 100 miles away from where she used to live, she spent most of her first year tiptoeing around the world outside of her basement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She remembers the day when a familiar face popped up near her host family during her walk with her son. One of his friends was in fishing attire, wandering around the street. The small-town summer attracted a lot of people from the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She panicked, dragging the stroller down the street. The horror was indescribable. Suddenly, she was once again sitting quietly in that smoke-filled room, not daring to make a single sound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She ran and ran and ran. The stroller slowed her down. She couldn’t remember how many people she ran into or how long she was running. She stopped at the back of a construction site with sweat dripping down her face. Inside the stroller, her son was crying hysterically. A construction worker walked past her, “Ma’am, are you alright?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next day she started to pack up. Within a week, she stepped onto the platform of a train south.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map on her car GPS slowly turns from red to yellow. The traffic in front of her starts to dissipate. She puts down her phone and brings her thoughts back to reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-day-till-the-mission">1 day till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thunders once again surround the city. After cooking dinner, she feels a bit nervous about the pickup tomorrow. It is not her first time, but she understands the risk never diminishes no matter how experienced she becomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow is the day. She clenches her fist. Her son is quietly on his phone at the kitchen table. His rare presence at the dinner table is amusing. She raises her eyebrows and asks what the special occasion is. He shrugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody knows that she is a part of the organization, not even the friend who initially introduced her to it. It is one of the rules to keep each mission as secretive as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After dinner, she leaves to top up gas. While she is pumping gas, a man comes up to her and asks for direction. She suspiciously answers with a brief description. Doesn’t everyone have a google map on their phone these days?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, he asks, “May I have your number?” She politely rejects while stating that she has a boyfriend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, that statement is a lie. She has barely dated since the escape over a decade ago. Besides the stress of being a single mother, she has trouble navigating through the dating world. Her brief period of therapy has been cut short due to the lack of money and time. She hasn’t had a chance to fully isolate herself from the nightmares that still revisit her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While studying accounting, she did meet a gentle young man at school. She was working and studying full time, leaving her son all day with the babysitter and the neighbour. He would come over after school and before the end of her shift and look after her son.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her son enjoyed every second of his company. They would play soccer in the park next to her apartment. On the weekend, he took him to bbq while she spent all day cleaning. So when he decided to end the relationship, her son was devastated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things went downhill once the conversation on next steps started to come up. He was eager to push the relationship to the next level, while she refused to rush into anything. Suddenly, the only father figure her son had ever had exited out of his life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She was called to school to pick up her misbehaving son after he got into a fight. The sun was shining down brightly on the dusty park swings. She sat next to him with the clenched fists and tears running down his bloody nose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that relationship, she’s been more careful with letting her guards down with anyone new. The next thing she knows, she is approaching her 40s, her son is almost an adult, and she is still alone and fragile in the world, scared to commit. How can she risk another incident that can lead to another devastation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She pulls up in her driveway. The LED light in her son’s bedroom is changing colour gradually. Tomorrow is the day. She is ready, yet when is she really ready?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-day-of-the-mission">The day of the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>She tiptoes downstairs. The moonlight spills all over the front of her front yard like milk. Cicadas sang vibrantly. She gets in her car. The sound of the engine floods her ears. She takes a deep breath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the designated spot, she parks her car and sits in complete darkness. She has to wait 30 minutes before aborting the pickup. She looks around the area. It’s 2:30 am. Every house on the street is sleeping on this peaceful night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suddenly, a tiny shadow on the corner scratches and breaks the silence of the night. A young girl appears under the street light. The girl is dragging a large duffel bag while wearing a baggy T-shirt, looking fragile and scared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She turns on her hazard lights. The girl’s eyes brighten up. The girl walks a little faster now, but the bag slows her down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She comes out and walks out of the car. “This is for the jewelry delivery?” The girl nods timidly and fixes the collar of her T-shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They drive off. She looks at the girl in the trunk. The girl, presumably Amy, is looking out the window nervously with her hands awkwardly placed on her tiny thighs. She hears Amy’s little voice in the back of the car, &amp;ldquo;Thank you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They arrive at the drop-off location. She opens the trunk and takes out Amy&amp;rsquo;s duffle bag. She turns around, and Amy is standing next to the car door with tears all over her face. &amp;ldquo;I am scared.&amp;rdquo; Amy can barely mutter a complete sentence, &amp;quot; I have never been alone before. I don’t know if I can make it&amp;hellip; I don’t know how to survive on my own&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She cuts her off sternly, &amp;ldquo;You will make it! You have to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She takes Amy’s hands in hers. She sees her younger teenage self in Amy’s sniffling. &amp;ldquo;You’re stronger than you can ever imagine. You have to believe it. Today will be the beginning of the toughest battle you’ll ever face, but you will make it. You have to tell yourself that. Now, go on and ring the doorbell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amy looks down for a minute and then nods. She watches Amy dragging the oversized duffle bag to the front door and ringing the doorbell. Someone comes out, confirms the details, and takes Amy in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She stands in the walkway that is blossoming with tulips. It’s a beautiful summer night. Another girl’s life is forever changed.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>