<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Random on Dahlia Zhou's Blog</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/categories/random/</link><description>Recent content in Random on Dahlia Zhou's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:51:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/categories/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pariah</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/pariah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:51:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/pariah/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/pariah/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Pariah" />&lt;p>The man with the mysterious illness and the woman with the nomadic blood met in the humming noise of the factory. Their daughter poisoned the wontons with too much thirteen-spice powder. Her slammed door was filled with disappointment of a failed academic career.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The violent and unwitting man held the hands of the daughter of a wealthy family who had a mistake in her belly. Their only surviving son was a young boy who could drown himself in the world of studies. When he arrived in the city, the limelight blinded his eyes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I was the fruit of the poisonous tree. The pariah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I arrived in my black robe and with the blade with the dark handle. When I limped into the hallway, hatred filled my prone-to-seizure brain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or I stepped onto the stage with my foreign features. The familiar music still haunted my every being. A domestic life with an ordinary woman suited me better than fame and fortune.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or I was the ambidextrous Gokturk princess who became a lesbian before it was cool. The gold fringes and red silk eclipsed that woman’s beauty and my despair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was cursed with an illness too. An ancient illness that plagued the land of pharaohs, Khans, Kings, and Shahs. The dark shamans begged for its arrival. They did a deal with Erlik.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The antidote saved me. Sir William Osler blessed the land with modern medicine. So I was me, finally. Not my obsession.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the bloodline ended, at least I could say that I traded the rat race for a moment of happiness. The cursed sadness became my source of strength.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Life could’ve been this easy? I wondered. Could I have saved them all? The non-existent ancestral shrine was full of bloodshed. &lt;em>Open your mouths&lt;/em>. I said. &lt;em>Here comes the dopamine&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by NEOM on Unsplash&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Cats I Met in Toronto Cat Rescue</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 17:35:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Cats I Met in Toronto Cat Rescue" />&lt;p>This post is dedicated to those beautiful feline friends I encountered while volunteering for Toronto Cat Rescue. In a tiny room, less than 5 square meters, we shared bonds that could not be understated by the limited time we spent together. These are cats who were born into misery, whose mom was abandoned, who had gone through drastic changes in their lives, or whose existence had been doomed. Yet through these difficult circumstances, they became the most resilient, the sweetest, and the most hopeful creatures I had ever seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cookie">Cookie&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cookie-2.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cookie-2_hu387499013c52eee6399ada8520b583a6_27029_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cookie-2_hu387499013c52eee6399ada8520b583a6_27029_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Cookie"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cookie was cuddly. He loved to eat and begged for treats. He was gorgeous.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sensei">Sensei&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/sensei.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/sensei_huec0609375015a401b4499d9fc65f1fb5_29057_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/sensei_huec0609375015a401b4499d9fc65f1fb5_29057_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Sensei"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sensei came with her kittens, who were named after the teenage ninja turtles. She was still nursing. An adventurous little one. She was always leading the whole family to escape the tiny adoption centre. She was beautiful and cuddly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="april-and-rafael">April and Rafael&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/april-rafael.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/april-rafael_hu0399c61e3307fe4babd12f6a612346e9_23794_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/april-rafael_hu0399c61e3307fe4babd12f6a612346e9_23794_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Rafael (On the left) and April (On the right)"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April and Rafael were troublemakers who were always wrestling. Rafael had a bad case of biting people for fun. April licked you when you tried to engage in kitten fighting behaviours.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="four-calioco-sisters">Four calioco sisters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/harsha.jpg"
width="300"
height="400"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/harsha_hu13691b4b0f867829e331154d937f205a_23807_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/harsha_hu13691b4b0f867829e331154d937f205a_23807_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Harsh, one of the calico sisters"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The four gorgeous girls were all diluted calico. Two of them were shy and reserved, while their sisters roamed around the centre. Their mom hated the new environment. Four girls got adopted pretty fast. I did fall in love with one of them, a shy little one named Adi. She was too shy to come and snuggle in any way, but her gorgeous and timid eyes were locked on me. She would stand on the edge of the cage, trying to gather the courage to reach out to me. That was the closest I’ve come to almost adopting another cat.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gerrard">Gerrard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/gerrard.jpg"
width="300"
height="533"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/gerrard_hu8b198ca585a95eb973522b69267ef98a_25282_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/gerrard_hu8b198ca585a95eb973522b69267ef98a_25282_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Gerrad"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="56"
data-flex-basis="135px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerrard was a loud little guy. His meowing could be heard from across PetSmart. He left on the day I met him to a gorgeous family. He would have a good life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="padou">Padou&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/padou.jpg"
width="300"
height="400"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/padou_hu962327032267833dcc5eea9f03bbc1f3_24757_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/padou_hu962327032267833dcc5eea9f03bbc1f3_24757_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Padou"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Padou, a French princess. From the limited interaction I had with her, she craved physical touch. She rubbed her head on mine against the cage.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="charlie">Charlie&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/charlie.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/charlie_hu12895b3d126910a401a3a3f0af0bf511_29714_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/charlie_hu12895b3d126910a401a3a3f0af0bf511_29714_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Charlie"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charlie was one of the sweetest boys I’ve ever met. He rubbed up on my legs with the force I’ve rarely encountered. He loved sitting on my laps and the tilapia breakfast. He stared at every shopper who stopped by the adoption centre, hoping they would be the one that took him home. Thank god, he got adopted after a week at the adoption centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Jae Park&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Unsplash&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>